#### **BUSINESS ANALYST II**

Professional Summary

Over 10 years of experience in developing, implementing and supporting business application systems. Areas of responsibility have included application design and specifications, database and system administration, development, quality assurance, installation and production support. Core Qualifications

Database Management \* Systems Design \* Report Analytics \* Professional \* Word Processing

Experience

Business Analyst II

August 2005 to March 2006 Hcsc il/4 Poteau, OK

- Produced Customer Operations performance metrics, forecasts, analysis and process management for all lines of business and operational activity.
- Responsible for development of ad hoc analysis for a variety of operational metrics.
- Ensured the integrity of all system data and work with field ops and customer care to communicate and enforce common measurement methods.
- Development and maintenance of client database tools to support efficient and timely reporting.
- Reports were done using a variety of tools, including Microsoft Access, SQL, crystal reports, macros, queries, Microsoft excel and word.
- Proactively communicate with client base on production issues and interpret production reports for clients as needed.
- Supervised production report quality and timeliness.

# Database Administrator/Analyst

December 1999 to January 2005 Deloitte il/4 FL

- Provide SQL server and Informix database administration support for over 100 applications including 4000 database instances with over 45 terabytes of data.
- Created a reporting/query manual for end-users to allow them to create and run their own queries for real-time processing.
- Designed database layout of development and production SQL Server and Informix databases, including capacity planning, database sizing, logical volume creation and physical data placement.
- Delivered RDBMS installation, physical database creation, backup and recovery strategy, database monitoring scripts, performance and tuning, stress testing, purge/archive strategy and disaster recovery testing.
- Mentored and trained junior database administrations in areas of performance tuning, troubleshooting and ongoing database administration support.
- Developed, tested and implemented backup and recovery procedure for the world's largest Peoplesoff HRMS databases.
- HRMS system runs 300,000 people through payroll in bi-weekly, weekly and semi-monthly cycles.

### IT Consultant

January 1998 to December 1999 Deloitte i1/4 West Palm Beach, OR

- Created a Microsoft Access database for internal IT management that allowed them to see all online screen changes, SQL changes and report changes.
- It contained push buttons that allowed them to view each type of change and in what system it occurred in.
- Acted as a liaison between developers and database administrators in diagnosing and troubleshooting complex Peoplesoff/Informix database issues.
- Developed and implemented Peoplecode, tables, panels, menus, SQL, SQR, Peopletool release and application upgrades.
- Applied Peoplesoft tax updates/patches to Informix databases on Sun Solaris Unix.

### Business Systems Developer

November 1994 to January 1998 Budget Rent A Car i1/4 Salem, STATE

- Created a Microsoft Access one-touch executive dashboard for management.
- This incorporated queries and macros that would produce excel reports that showed daily profits/losses and operational run time/down time
- Key participant in development, performance enhancement, and maintenance of Peoplesoft Human Resources Management systems version 5.0, 5.11, 5.12.
- Developed and implemented Peoplecode, tables, panels, menus, SQL, SQR, Peopletool releases and application upgrades.
- Responsible for COBOL revisions, hardware/software configuration, network support and performance tuning.
- Responsible for data conversion for a 25 location conversion which included 5000+ active employees to the Peoplesoft system.
- Systems Administrator for UNIX AIX V4.13 running on an RS/6000.
- Provided support to employees using Primac, the primary financial reporting system.
- Assisted in the definition, development and conversion of 600 users to the labor collection system.
- Managed the time keeping system including hardware and software support.
- Supported development of all manufacturing and financial reports using UDMS/Unidata.

# Education

bACHELOR OF SCIENCE: COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS, Oct 26, 1991 DEVRY INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, LOMBARD GPA: 4.0/4.0 COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS GPA: 4.0/4.0

MONTEREY PENINSULA COLLEGE Technical Summary DBMS: Sql Server V7 and 2000 System Administration, Informix Online Database Administration, Informix Stored Procedures, Performance Tuning, SQL, Advanced SQL, Managing and Optimizing, Oracle Intro to SQL UNIX: Basic Unix, Unix System Administration, Vi Editor Peoplesoft: Peopletools I and II, Intro to HR, Intro to Payroll, SQL/SQR, Data Management Tools, Peoplecode, Intro to Benefits, Benefit Administration Skills

ad, AIX, backup, Basic, Benefits, bi, capacity planning, COBOL, hardware, conversion, crystal reports, client, clients, customer care, data conversion, Data Management, Database Administration, databases, database, database creation, Database Management, DBMS, disaster recovery, Editor, financial reports, financial reporting, HR, Human Resources Management, Informix, Informix Online, IT management, layout, macros, Managing, Microsoft Access, Microsoft excel, excel, 2000, word, network support, Oracle, Payroll, Peoplecode, Peoplesoft HRMS, Peoplesoft, Peopletools I, process management, quality, RDBMS, real-time, reporting, RS/6000, scripts, Sun Solaris, SQL, SQL, Server, SQR, strategy, System Administration, Systems Design, tables, tax, software support, troubleshooting, type, UNIX, Unix System Administration, upgrades, Vi, view, Word Processing